[{"question": "Which of the following matrices can be solved using np.linalg.solve(A, B)", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "A = np.array([[a1, a2, a3], [a2, a3, a4]])<br>B = np.array([b1, b2, b3])", "correct": false}, {"answer": "A = np.array([[a1, a2, a3], [a2, a3, a4], [a3, a4 ,a5]])<br>B = np.array([b1, b2])", "correct": false}, {"answer": "A = np.array([[a1, a2, a3], [a2, a3, a4], [a3, a4, a5]])<br>B = np.array([b1, b2, b3])", "correct": true}, {"answer": "A = np.array([[a1, a2], [a2, a3], [a3, a4]])<br>B = np.array([b1, b2])", "correct": false}], "tag": "numpy applications", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}, {"question": "If B and X are row vectors, then the expression $b_1 x_1 + b_2 x_2 + b_3 x_3$ can be expressed as", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "B.T . X.T", "correct": false}, {"answer": "B . X", "correct": false}, {"answer": "B.T . X", "correct": false}, {"answer": "B . X.T", "correct": true}], "tag": "vectors applications", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}, {"question": "x = np.linspace(1, 5, 3); y = np.array([3, 9, 27])<br>Y = interp1d(x, y, kind='quadratic', bounds_error=False)<br>xfit = np.linspace(-1, 8)<br>print(Y(xfit))<br><br>The above code will", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "Raise an error", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Print Y() values for the x-range (-1, 8)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Print Y() values for the x-range (1, 5) and NaN for the rest", "correct": true}, {"answer": "None of the above", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy applications", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}, {"question": "If the eigenvalues of matrix A are complex, then we can be certain that the matrix A", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "is symmetric", "correct": false}, {"answer": "is a non-square matrix", "correct": false}, {"answer": "has all the elements as complex numbers", "correct": false}, {"answer": "is non-symmetric", "correct": true}], "tag": "eigenvalues eigen", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}, {"question": "For a 2 x 2 matrix with all values being real, and having 2 eigenvalues, if 1-2j is one of the eigenvalues, what is the other eigenvalue", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "1 + 2j", "correct": true}, {"answer": "-2j", "correct": false}, {"answer": "-1 -2j", "correct": false}, {"answer": "-1+2j", "correct": false}], "tag": "eigenvalues eigen", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}, {"question": "For an N x N matrix, the number of eigenvalues", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "will always be equal to N", "correct": false}, {"answer": "can never be more than N", "correct": true}, {"answer": "can be less or more than N", "correct": false}, {"answer": "will always be less than N", "correct": false}], "tag": "eigenvalues eigen", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}, {"question": "Find the product of the eigenvalues for the matrix:<br>np.array([[1, 2, 3], [3, 2, 1], [2, 1, 0]])", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "-8", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Need more information", "correct": false}, {"answer": "0", "correct": true}, {"answer": "1", "correct": false}], "tag": "eigenvalues eigen", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}, {"question": "Find the sum of all the eigenvalues of the matrix:<br>np.array([[1, 2, 3], [3, 2, 1], [2, 0, 1]])", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "0", "correct": false}, {"answer": "4", "correct": true}, {"answer": "Need more information", "correct": false}, {"answer": "6", "correct": false}], "tag": "eigenvalues eigen", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}, {"question": "If the eigenvalues of the Hessian matrix for a function are all negative, then we are at a", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "minimum", "correct": false}, {"answer": "saddle point", "correct": false}, {"answer": "maximum", "correct": true}, {"answer": "Need more information", "correct": false}], "tag": "eigenvalues hessian eigen", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}, {"question": "If the eigenvectors of a matrix A are orthogonal, then we can be certain  that matrix A is a ", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "symmetric matrix", "correct": true}, {"answer": "asymmetric matrix", "correct": false}, {"answer": "lower triangular matrix", "correct": false}, {"answer": "There is no inference", "correct": false}], "tag": "eigenvectors eigen", "lecture_file": "17_linear_algebra_2"}]